As in 1997 the Federal Motor Vehicles Safety Standard requires manufactures to put in some kind of locking magnetism on there seat belts so they can be used with child safety seats.
The belt that I'm holding here is a lap only belt this belt locks with a bar inside it that pulls when the belt buckle is parallel to the belt path itself.
When it is turned perpendicular it releases and allows the belt to slide freely this is important because using it with a child's restraint.
If you tighten it this way but in some cases depending on this starts and where this lines up if it actually lines up in the belt path like this it is not going to lock.
So it is important that it will be the belt needs to be above the locking magnetism.
Another form of the belt that you would find is a lap shoulder belt most of these are freely and again as I said as in 1997 they made a prevision in these belts that would allow them to lock.
The prevision on this belt is that you pull the belt slowly all the way out the belt then switches and if you can hear that it is ranching back in it remains lock until it retracts fully.
You would find this on General Motors product, Ford products and most imported cars. Chrysler uses what is known as a cinching latch plate the plate itself here at the latch has a siding number that locks it.
It may or may not be enough to keep the belt locked on that steep in that case we have a thing known as a locking clip.
The locking clip is always applied within a inch of a latch plate and a locking clip could be used with a belt that has no locking magnetism that is older then 1997.